<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Papers on Open History Map</title><link>https://openhistorymap.github.io/paper/</link><description>Recent content in Papers on Open History Map</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 12:25:26 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://openhistorymap.github.io/paper/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Participatory Models in Archaeology: Wiki and Open Access Platforms</title><link>https://openhistorymap.github.io/paper/archeofoss19/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 12:25:26 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://openhistorymap.github.io/paper/archeofoss19/</guid><description>Abstract: The paper proposed herein presents three events organized in 2018 and tries to find a common thread through these experiences. Two of these events were organized thanks to the collaboration between Trentino Alto Adige Wiki and Arc-Team, while the third was conceived and organized by Open History Map, an association based in Bologna. The three events deal with very different topics but have in common the close collaboration between the public, Wikimedia volunteers and researchers.</description></item><item><title>GEOCONTEXT AND CHCONTEXT GEOGRAPHIC INFORMATION IN CULTURAL HERITAGE</title><link>https://openhistorymap.github.io/paper/isprs_2018/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 12:25:26 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://openhistorymap.github.io/paper/isprs_2018/</guid><description>Abstract: Internet presence and applications are central for modern museums and cultural institutions. Even more it is important to facilitate and standardize the user experience in order to create a standard quality level and, for the institutions, it is important to simplify configuration operations bound to the creation of the visualized elements and the explorations of the spaces. This demo covers both the technologies underneath the GeoContext tool and the CHContext visualization generator as well as the possible targets and applications.</description></item><item><title>Open History Map</title><link>https://openhistorymap.github.io/paper/aec_28_2017/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 12:25:26 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://openhistorymap.github.io/paper/aec_28_2017/</guid><description>Abstract: OpenHistoryMap aspires to become the open source geographical system for archaeological information, both from an academic and an educational point of view. There are many fragmented online web-GIS experiences targeted at very specific projects, but no tool enables a broader overview of both research and studies. For these reasons, in order to create an Open Access platform, one of the most important aspects is the creation of tools that can facilitate both the sharing of archaeological spatial and temporal information as well as the easy reuse of the generated data.</description></item><item><title>Open history map - a new approach to open access for archaeology and cultural heritage</title><link>https://openhistorymap.github.io/paper/dh15_7419557/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 12:25:26 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://openhistorymap.github.io/paper/dh15_7419557/</guid><description>Abstract: Open Access is a growing idea in many fields. Archaeology is at the moment a bit behind. The reasons can be found in many aspects: First of all, archaeological data is not easy to monetize, and it is not easy to standardize, and this has pushed the creation of many “archaeologies”, and that is visible from the data gathered during expeditions. There are many fragmented webgis experiences targeted at very specific projects, but there is no tool that enables a more broad overview of both researches and studies.</description></item></channel></rss>